Joint Board, Fur, Leather & Machine Workers Union Records 5685
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series III - GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE
  - Sub-Series A. Joint Board, 1968
    - Sub-Series 1. General Correspondence, 1968
      - American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 22)
        Invitation to the Fight Back Rally; a bill discussing the limitation on deportation and denaturalization
      - B - Miscellaneous, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 23)
      - Blood Bank, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 24)
      - Burt, Sam - Houses (January-March), 1968 (Box 37, Folder 25)
        Financial information; correspondence re fixing the terrace doors; inspection reports
      - Burt, Sam - Houses (April-June), 1968 (Box 37, Folder 26)
        Financial information; notes to tenants re representative government complaints from "cooperators" re construction of apartments
      - Burt, Sam - Houses (July-August) (Sept.-Dec.), 1968 (Box 37, Folder 27-28)
        Financial correspondence; inspection reports; letter from cooperator's council to Henry Foner re their dissatisfaction with Abbott & Adams, the operating management (parking lot lights, Scrubber installation) complaints about the terrace doors
      - Butcher Workman, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 29)
      - Butchers District Council, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 30)
      - C - Miscellaneous, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 31)
        Cornell University labor studies program information
      - Cammer & Shapiro, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 32)
        Legal 'advice' re death benefit fund; vacation fund Local 88F; new rules for setting aside elections; new anti- discrimination law ADEA for those aged 40-64; ruling that you can keep a list of employees who have voted at an election
      - Christmas - parties, cards, etc., 1968 (Box 37, Folder 33)
      - Clippings, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 34)
        From WWD, NYT, etc.
      - Community Services Committee, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 35)
      - Consumer Assembly, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 36)
        Invitation/information to assembly, January 13, 1968
      - Contracts Incoming - list, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 37)
      - Contracts - Renewal, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 38)
      - D - Miscellaneous, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 39)
      - Dubin, Mel - election campaign propaganda; 13th Congressional District; list of union members within this district, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 40)
      - Equal Opportunity Commission (EE0), 1968 (Box 37, Folder 41)
        Notification to Joint Board that they did not file EEO-3
      - F - Miscellaneous, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 42)
      - Financial Contributions, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 43-44)
        Thank you letters, request and acknowledgement of above
      - Freedom Festival, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 45)
        Plans, invitations and Foner's speech at this benefit in celebration of Negro History Week
      - Fur Information and Fashion Council, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 46)
        Information about fur advertising and notice re the First International Fur Congress
      - FIFC - College Fur Try-On, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 47)
        Information about college fur campaign
      - G - Miscellaneous, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 48)
      - Greece - American Committee for Democracy & Freedom, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 49)
        Information re military dictatorship in Greece and how this affects the International Conference of Free Trade Unions; letters, speeches (unsigned) urging US government to get involved from AFL-CIO
      - H - Miscellaneous, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 50)
        Clipping re Otto Hall obituary
      - Histradrut - routine, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 51)
      - Housing - miscellaneous, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 52)
        Proposal for housing in Sheepshead Bay, Brooklyn
      - Israel Bonds, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 53)
        Correspondence between Joint Board and Israel re purchase of Israel Bonds
      - J - Miscellaneous, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 54)
        Correspondence to Foner from J. Javits thanking him for election supports
      - Joint Board Annual Meeting, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 55)
        Preparations, invitations, RSVP's
      - Joint Board Annual Meeting, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 56-57)
        Agenda, proposed program, audit information; Henry Foner's report; minutes
      - Joint Board By-law amendments, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 58)
        Local union constitution from 1964
      - Joint Board By-laws amendments, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 59)
        Proposed changes due to merger with Jt. Bd. Council 3
      - Joint Board - Joint Council 3 Merger, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 60)
        Correspondence re the bylaw changes due to the merger
      - Joint Board Staff, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 61)
        Weekend at Laurels Hotel
      - K - Miscellaneous, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 62)
      - Kennedy, Robert F. - Memorial Meeting, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 63)
        Clippings from memorial given by the fur industry
      - King, Martin Luther Jr., 1968 (Box 37, Folder 64)
        Memorial Service notices; speech in honor of Martin Luther King by Reverend David A. Giles
      - Kottler, Joseph, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 65)
        Election campaign materials; list of members who live in the congressional district; Kottler campaign papers
      - Labor Leadership for Peace, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 66)
        Copy of Labor Voice for Peace, April 1960 published by Labor Leadership for Peace
      - Labor Press, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 67)
        Constitution of the International Labor Press Association; Code of Ethics; ILPA Reporter, September 1968; ILPA Directory of Member Publications
      - Labor Press, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 68)
        Speaking of Labor Unions (ref. manual of terms); advertising guides, PR guide; local publications guide; various pamphlets published by the ILPA
      - Lasalle Letter Company, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 69)
        Correspondence re stationary
      - Legislation, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 70)
        Minimum wage discussion and other correspondence
      - Legislation, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 71)
        Lists
      - Liberal Party, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 72)
        1968 State Legislative Program
      - Liberal Party - Labor Committee, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 73)
      - Liberal Party - Vietnam Dialogue, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 74)
        Organization chart for NY Liberal Party; routine
      - Liberals for McCarthy, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 75)
        Notices of meetings; 8/2/68 Bensonhurst News - Article about Newsgroup (above) formed - Henry Foner and Joint Board were supporters of this group; correspondence from various people indicating their support for the group; copies of articles support McCart
      - McCarthy, Senator Eugene, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 76)
        Election campaign; notices about the formation of Northern California Labor Committee for Eugene McCarthy
      - Meeting Notices/Summaries for the Joint Board Activities, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 77)
      - Mississippi - National Committee for Free Elections Newsletters, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 78)
      - N - Miscellaneous, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - National Elections, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 2)
        Reminder for members to vote
      - National Foundation of Health, Welfare & Pension Plans, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 3)
        Legal-legislative reporter news bulletins
      - New York Urban Coalition, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 4-5)
        Minutes of annual meeting, opening address and a summary of highlights; by-laws; certificate of incorporation; report - Emergency Convocation: The Urban Coalition; routine, notices of meetings, etc.
      - Newark Riots, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 6)
        Senate Investigation clippings
      - O - Miscellaneous, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 7)
      - O'Dwyer, Paul - Election Campaign, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 8)
        List of supporters; election propaganda
      - Office Memos - Routine, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 9)
      - Organization Committee - Routine, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 10)
      - P - Miscellaneous, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 11)
      - Parking Lots - Sale, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 12)
        Legal, financial information
      - Peace Organizations, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 13)
        Information regarding upcoming rally in Central park
      - Political Action Committee, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 14)
        Meeting notices, thank you letters, etc.
      - Poor People's Campaign, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 15)
        Information about Poor People's March to Washington
      - R - Miscellaneous, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 16)
      - Retirement Committee, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 17)
        Meeting minutes, monthly list of events
      - S - Miscellaneous, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 18)
      - SSEU - Merger, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 19)
        Details of merger between SSEU and Local 371
      - SANE, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 20)
        Newsletters of action on disarmament and the peace race, January & April 1968
      - State of Israel Bonds, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 21)
        Correspondence re the purchase of bonds
      - TEMPO - correspondence, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 22-23)
        General/routine correspondence re publication of TEMPO
      - U - Miscellaneous, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 24)
      - Unions - Miscellaneous, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 25)
        Information from United Farm Workers re the Giumarra Grape Strike & Delano Grape Strike; general correspondence
      - V-W - Miscellaneous, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 26)
  - Sub-Series B. LOCALS, 1968
    - Sub-Series 4. Locals - 1968, 1968
      - Local 48, form letters; notices of meetings, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 27)
      - Local 48, shop correspondence, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 28)
      - Local 48, worker correspondence, A-Z, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 29)
      - Local 88, form letters, routine, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 30)
      - Local 88, miscellaneous, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 31)
    - Sub-Series 7. Shop Correspondence, 1968
      - A-B, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 32)
      - C-D including dye section, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 33)
      - E-F, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 34)
      - Fur Processors Association, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 35)
      - G-H, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 36)
      - I-J, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 37)
      - K-L, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 38)
      - M-N, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 39)
      - O-P-Q-R, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 40)
      - S-Z, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 41)
    - Sub-Series 8. Worker Correspondence, 1968
      - A-Z, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 42)
  - Sub-Series A. JOINT BOARD, 1969
    - Sub-Series 1. General Correspondence, 1969
      - A - Miscellaneous, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 43)
      - AFL - City, State, National, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 44)
        Information about Empire State Labor-Management Exhibit; Richard Nixon's presidency
      - AMC&BW - Chicago correspondence, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 45)
        Thank you from Henry Foner to Patrick Gorman for support for protection of animal species threatened with extinction; notice of Lillian Hanna's death (Executive Assistant's wife); routine correspondence
      - AMC&BW - Chicago correspondence, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 46)
        Notices of settlements arrived at without striking; requests to Guy Pinney at Dept. of Industrial Engineer to conduct a time study at Seton Leather Company; routine correspondence
      - AMC&BW of NA - Chicago correspondence, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 47)
        News of the Neuhoff Strike and International denial of strike funds
      - AMC&BW - Circular Letters, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 48)
        Statement of civil rights policy; financial statement of international union
      - AMC&BW - Fur & Leather Department, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 49)
      - AMC&BW - Other than Chicago, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 50)
        Information about the Borden Settlement
      - AMC&BW - Neuhoff Strike settlement news, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 52)
        Iowa Beef Strike
      - AMC&BW, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 53)
        Staffgrams
      - American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 54)
        Story of a WWII Japanese-American who was relocated and a plea to prevent it from occurring again
      - B - Miscellaneous, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 55)
      - Burt, Sam - Houses, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 56)
        By-laws
      - Burt, Sam - Houses, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 57)
        Financial & legal information; audit information; financial - summary management report
      - Burt, Sam - Houses - General - January/March, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 58)
        Rules & regulations; information about switch from Abbott & Adams, Allison Management; notices about payments for various items/services within the building; management inspection reports
      - Burt, Sam - Houses - General - April/June, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 59)
        Financial information, checks paid, etc.; survey of Sam Burt houses insurance requirements
      - Burt, Sam - Houses - General - August/December, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 60)
        Financial information, checks needing to be signed, paid, etc.; notices from law offices of Newmark, Boehm and Rosenstein or Allison Management; balance sheets; letter from Jack Myles to Allison Management Corp. re financial troubles of the Sam Burt House
      - Burt, Sam - Houses - Proposal, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 61)
        Proposal, financial estimates & preliminary plans, qualification of participants, etc.
      - Butchers District Council, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 62)
      - Butcher Workman, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 63)
        Copies of articles, notices, submitted for publication
      - C - Miscellaneous, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 64)
        Pamphlet from the Center for the study of Democratic Institutions
      - Cammer & Shapiro, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 65)
        Letter to Murry Bergtraum re possible Joint Board participation in a lawsuit against companies that fix prices of antibiotics; notification about law changes that affect the Joint Board
      - Clippings - newspaper, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 66)
      - Contracts, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 67)
        Lists with expiration dates
      - Contracts - Renewals, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 68-69)
      - Contracts - Incoming, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 70)
      - Cornell University, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 71)
        A handbook for advisors of the Union Vocational Advisory Project in the High Schools by Dr. George A. Gazetas - published by Cornell University
      - Cornell University - The Visible Union in Time of Stress by Community Services Committee of NYC Central Labor Council, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 72)
      - Cornell University - NYSSILR, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 73)
        Union-University Urban Affairs Program - Annual Report; information about the ILR School; calendar for Labor Studies/Spring 1969
      - Cornell University, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 74)
        Information about classes, seminars & presentations relating to labor; routine correspondence
      - Cornell University, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 75)
        Presentation from the 11th Annual Wilhelm Weinberg Seminar "Chaos or the Responsive Society"; classwork from a labor studies class
      - Cost of Living Index Figures - CPI's, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 76)
      - Embargo on Russian Furs, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 1)
        A study of the embargo of 7 soviet furs
      - Embargo on Russian Furs, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 2)
        Correspondence involving various reports on the above; plea to politicians for support to relieve embargo; correspondence re Muskie bill on E-W trade; statement of American Fur Merchants Association
      - Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 3-4)
        Forms and correspondence re Joint Board failure to file EE0-3 and the Joint Labor- Management Apprenticeship Committee failure to file Apprenticeship Report EEO-2
      - F - Miscellaneous, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 5)
      - Finances, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 6)
        Audit and other information relating to costs
      - Financial Contributions, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 7-8)
        Routine requests and thank you's
      - Freedom Festival - February 22, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 9)
        Shirley Chisholm received Freedom Award; a play "Roots of Unity" by Milton Ost
      - Fur Information and Fashion Council, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 10)
        Operating budget, 1969; recommended programs for 1970; memo to policy committee re lot money accounting with the International Fur Trade Federation; a guide "What Every Woman Should Know About Furs"
      - G - Miscellaneous, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 11)
        Thank you letter for fruit basket from Harold E. Grotta to Henry Foner
      - Greece, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 12)
        Plea for help from the North America Greek Relief Fund; letter to H. Foner from Demitris Souliotis of United Syndicalistic Anti- dictatorship movement re trade union support of the movement; letter from H. Foner to NAGRF giving his consent for them to use
      - H - Miscellaneous, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 13)
      - Harpers & Row Publishers, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 14)
        Personnel policies & practices; collective bargaining agreement; employee benefit plans, etc.
      - Histradrut - routine, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 15)
      - I - Miscellaneous, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 16)
      - Imports - Correspondence - Fur, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 17-18)
        Re restricting imports because it creates competition for domestic markets and decreased employment for the fur workers union and bill before Congress that would restrict imports; letters to Javits requesting his support; letter from John B. Rehm to Javit
      - Imports - Fur - General, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 19)
        Mink Fur skins, a report to the President on Investigation No. 332-54 Under Section 332 of the Tariff Act of 1930 by the U.S. Tariff Commission
      - Imports - Fur - General, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 20)
        Correspondence re H.R. 6694 Burke Bill which would admit duty-free imports of raw mink each year = 40% of domestic consumption of raw and dressed minks; news articles re unions protests against British Furs; Johnson does not sympathize with import restric
      - Imports - Fur - General, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 21)
        Facts on the U.S. & foreign raw mink skin industry by American Fur Merchants Association; statement by H. Foner before Senate Finance Committee; statement by Abe Feinglass before the U.S. Tariff Commission hearings on mink imports
      - Imports - Fur - General, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 22)
        Report to members by the American Fur Merchants re impact of imported mink on the domestic industry; statement on behalf of Scandinavian Fur Agency at the hearings on tariff and trade proposals before the Committee on Ways & Means; brief of American Fur M
      - Imports - Milk, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 23)
        Correspondence re FDA ruling that canned milk is not under the protection of the Import Milk Act
      - Imports - Shoe & Leather, 1967-1969 (Box 39, Folder 24)
        Membership bulletin leather industry statistics; correspondence protesting shoe imports and the increasing number of them
      - Imports - Shoe & Leather, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 25)
        Correspondence - limiting imports
      - Imports - Shoe & Leather, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 26-27)
        "The impact of imports on the U.S. Footwear Manufacturing Industry" a packet of information put together by the National Affairs Committee of the National Footwear Manufacturers Association - facts, proposals for action, speeches and news releases; S 2984
      - Imports - Wild Life (I/WL), 1969 (Box 39, Folder 28)
        HR 11363 - Reports on the bill and documents of changes made January 28, 1969 - August 2, 1969
      - I/WL Reports on endangered species to accompany various bills (HR 11363 & HR 11618), 1969 (Box 39, Folder 29)
      - I/WL - U.S. Government printed hearing on Endangered Species for S 2984 & HR 11618 - includes amendments to the above as approved by the management and labor organizations in the U.S. Fur Industry, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 30-31)
      - I/WL - correspondence without dates, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 32)
      - I/WL - Petitions, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 33)
        Leather workers from Newark petitioning against the passage of S 2984 - the endangered species bill
      - I/WL - Various reports, statements and facts regarding HR 11618/ S 2984 from various unions, fur manufacturers, government, and others interested in the cause, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 34-37)
      - I/WL - Survey import/export figures; statements before Committee of Eugene Dreisin, President of American Fur Merchants & Herman Fingelheim, Executive Vice President of Brooklyn Better Bleach, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 38)
      - I/WL - Statements of John Perry, Asst. Director, National Zoological Park, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 39)
      - I/WL - Tanners' Council of American, Arnold Mayer, Legislative Representative of AMC&BW of N.A., 1969 (Box 39, Folder 40)
      - I/WL - Statements by Edward Classen of the Fur Brokers Association of America, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 41)
      - I/WL - Correspondence re HR 4812 which deals with alligator legislation; documentation of changes to HR 4812 as done by the administration, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 42)
      - I/WL - Statement by George Greenberg, Executive Vice President, Associated Fur Manufacturers; James Sharp, counsel to major segments of the American Fur Industry before the Subcommittee on Energy, Natural Resources and the Environment, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 43)
      - I/WL - Letter from Arnold Mayer to Henry Foner re passage of endangered species and its passage through the House & the Senate. Contains language put in at the request of the AMC, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 44)
      - Joint Board - Annual Meeting - Arrangements, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 45)
        Menus, rooms, correspondence with Michael Piatt regarding the purchase of attach cases that will be stamped
      - Joint Board - Annual Meeting - Delegates, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 46-47)
        Lists of meeting attendees and general information
      - Joint Board - Annual Meeting - Guests - RSVP's, 1969 (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Joint Board Installation Meeting, 1969 (Box 40, Folder 2)
        Routine correspondence letting appropriate persons know about the installation of officers & board members, agenda
      - Joint Board Staff, 1969 (Box 40, Folder 3)
        Homowack Weekend, January 30 - February 2, 1969
      - L - Miscellaneous, 1969 (Box 40, Folder 4)
      - Labor Leadership - Assembly for Peace, 1969 (Box 40, Folder 5)
        Brochures & leaflets promoting their cause "Peace"
      - Labor Press, 1969 (Box 40, Folder 6)
        ILPA Reporter - January, June, October; the 1969 directory of Member Publications; ILPA Constitutional Amendment Proposals for the 1969 convention
      - Labor Press - National Conference of Christians & Jews, 1969 (Box 40, Folder 7)
        Tempo, the FLM publication won the Brotherhood Award as sponsored by the above; ILPA - Journalistic Awards Banquet; FLM Joint Board Tempo won an award for local union publications
      - Langer, David Co., 1969 (Box 40, Folder 8)
        A actuarial consulting company working with the FLM. Reports about retirement funds, Medicaid and welfare funds are included; a personal & confidential letter from David Langer to Henry Foner re welfare fund consulting plan
      - Lasalle Letter Co., 1969 (Box 40, Folder 9)
        Routine re changing letterhead on stationery
      - Leaflet of Month, 1969 (Box 40, Folder 10)
        From AFL-CIO
      - Legislation - correspondence, 1969 (Box 40, Folder 11)
        Letters to congressmen re possible change in striking worker unemployment insurance benefit re pay TV and its effect on the workingman and shoe and leather imports
      - Legislation - Unemployment Insurance, 1969 (Box 40, Folder 12)
        Joint Board's efforts to defeat Nixon's proposal to amend the unemployment insurance law for striking workers; Nixon's proposal to change UI/press release
      - Liberal Party, 1969 (Box 40, Folder 13)
        Correspondence between Foner & Mayor Lindsay re labor day statement; address by H. Foner at the Annual Liberal Party Dinner
      - M - Miscellaneous, 1969 (Box 40, Folder 14)
      - Meeting Notices, 1969 (Box 40, Folder 15)